Guide to the William Bradbury Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Bradbury papers
1837-1900
GEN MSS 210
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.25
(1 box)
Correspondence regarding the publishing business of Bradbury and Evans, as well as correspondence regarding the Bradbury family. There are also several poems.
Bradbury, William, 1799-1869
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase from C. A. Stonehill on the Library Associates Fund, 1939.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of materials pertaining to William Bradbury.
Publishers -- England; Poetry; Bradbury, William, 1799-1869; Bradbury & Evans
- Correspondence, 1850 May 18
  - Acton, Eliza, 1799-1859. ALS to Mrs. Loudon, editor of the Ladies' Companion, Denmark Place, 1850 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Referring to W. Bradbury's illness.
  - Aucutt, George Burchett. ALS to W. Bradbury, Whitefriars, 1868 Jul 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bradbury, John. 2 ALS to W. Bradbury, Whitefriars, 1868 Jun 16, Jul 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bradbury, W. Laurence. ALS to "My dear Uncle Charles", Whitefriars, London, E.C., 1900 Jul 18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bradbury, William, Proprietor of Punch. ALS to Dear Old Friends with "a short codicil to add a bit of spice for the cup" at the Wayzgoose of 1868, [1868?] Jul 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Laid in: MS copy of the inscription, probably in W. Bradbury's hand, dated 1867 Jul 29 to John Knowles, Esq., "on the occasion of the Amateur Performance in Manchester in and of the Bennett Fund by the Proprietors of Punch."
  - Bradbury, Evans, and co., London.
    - LS in manuscript to Messrs. Southgate and Basset, Whitefriars, 1862 Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - LS in manuscript referring to the interests of the Misses Thackeray in their father's works, Whitefriars, London, 1864 Feb 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carpenter, Charles. ALS to "Mr. Punch" [W. Bradbury], Liverpool, 1848 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chambers, Anne (Kirkwood). ALS to W. Bradbury, [Edinburgh], 1837 Sep 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chambers, William, 1800-1883. 2 ALS to Mr. Bradbury, Edinburgh, 1837 Jan 14, 1865 Jan 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cole, Sir Henry, 1808-1882. ALS to Messrs. Bradbury & Evans, London, 1864 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    The letter refers to the interests of Mr. Thackeray's daughters in their father's works.
  - [Evans, Frederick Mullett, d. 1870?] ALS to [Mr. Bradbury], signed F. M. E.?, London, [n.y.] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Concerning the interests of Thackeray's daughters in the publication of his works.
  - Garrick Club, London, 1861 Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Manuscript application for proposed membership of William Bradbury to the Garrick Club, written and signed by S. B. [Shirley Brooks]. Mr. Bradbury's name was proposed by John Leech and seconded by 23 members. For S. B.'s monogram, see p. 63 of Spielman's History of Punch, N. Y., 1865.
  - Jerrold, Douglas William, 1803-1857. ALS to Mr. Bradbury, [n.p.], [n.y.] Tuesday morning (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lemon, Mark, 1809-1870. 2 ANS in an unknown hand, [London], 1866 Jun (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Accompanied a token presented to Mark Lemon, from his old friends, W. Bradbury & F. M. Evans, etc.
  - Lucas, Samuel, 1818-1868. 7 ALS to Messrs. Bradbury & Evans, Burlington Gardens, 1864 Dec 17-1865 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Referring to non-payment of money due.
  - Mayhew, Horace, 1816-1872. ALS to Mr. Bradbury, [Kensington], 1868 Jul 12 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Sending his good wishes and announcing his coming marriage.
  - Milliken, E. J. ALS to Mr. Agnew, Woodcote, 83, Loughborough Park, 1892 Oct 18 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Regarding the loss of a brother [William Bradbury].
  - Roscoe, Thomas, 1791-1871. ALS to [Mr. Bradbury?], Camden, New Town, 1844 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Mentioning Marliani's History of modern Spain from the accession of Ferdinand VII, Count Toreno's History of Spain up to Ferdinand VII, and M. de Simonde's Essays upon the Constitution of Free States.
  - Russell. ALS to Mr. Greving, [n.p.], 1852 Jul 3 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Tatham & Proctor, London. 2 LS to C. S. Agnew, [n.p.], 1900 Mar 6, Jul 5 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Concerning Mr. Bradbury's estate.
  - Wills, William Henry, 1810-1880. ALS to W. Bradbury, Edinburgh, 1843 Jan 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Concerning his visit to Messrs. Chambers of Edinburgh.
- Writings, n.d.
  - Amicus, pseud. MS copy in an unknown hand, of a poem entitled: The Nature of True Riches, signed Amicus, [n.p.] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lindley, Nathaniel Lindley, baron, 1828-1921. An account of the estate under the will of William Bradbury, deceased as of 1898 Dec 25, [n.p.], 1899 Apr (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Same date as death of Mrs. Sarah Bradbury. A MS copy in an unknown hand, from "The Right Hon. Sir Nathaniel Lindley, the Master of the Rolls."
  - "Lines written on the top of the old spire of Bakewell Church", [n.p.], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    MS copy in an unknown hand.
  - Wills, Mrs. I. Autograph poem addressed to "Madame B" [Bradbury], [n.p.], The Cottage of Athall, [n.y.] Friday (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Theatre programs, newsheets, and miscellaneous envelopes (Box 1, Folder 26)